Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
TYPHOON FAMILY
Where's my IOU?
My promissory note.
I can't find it.
AUGUST 1989
It's just as I told Mr. Ha, sir.
Just look, Mr. Pyo.
There was a page
with records of loans right here,
so I tore it and destroyed it.
I went through everything daily
since we were at the Ulchiro office,
but I couldn't find it.
That small scrap of paper can't have gone
anywhere on its own, can it?
I've searched everywhere,
but I still couldn't find it!
Are you sure Tae-poong doesn't have it?
Please think about it, Mr. Pyo.
We… I mean, no.
Typhoon Trading had to resort
to relocating to this old place.
Let's say Tae-poong has that note.
Do you think that hotheaded kid
would stay quiet?
He'd have caused a scene
at your office already.
As for the money you gave me,
I'll make sure to return it to you.
I wasn't in my right mind
when I accepted it.
-Here.
-Goodness.
HANAM UNIVERSITY HOSPITAL
FUNERAL HOME
I can't accept this.
Please don't put me on the spot like this.
I heard your husband's business
is struggling.
I'm saying that I don't know anything
about that promissory note you're after.
We won't make the same offer again.
-All right, then--
-Wait!
Could I have some time to think about it?
My financial situation is…
Well, it's in terrible shape.
I swear I'll return every penny.
I've done enough, haven't I?
It's about time you gave up, all right?!
What's the matter?
I hear your husband's business went under.
Does it feel like it's all over now?
You thought wrong.
You have your kid.
That kid should get
to finish school, right?
-What are you--
-Stop squealing and find my note.
-Then we're all good.
-What do you…
What are you saying?
Why are you even mentioning my child?
Why are you dragging my kid into this?
Why would you mention my baby?!
Find it.
That's all I need.
You're so sweet, Mi-ja.
My goodness.
Mi-ja, could you teach Beom
how to clean up his things?
SCHOOL NEWSLETTER
GREEN MOTHERS' CLUB DUTIES NOTICE
Make sure to teach him, okay?
Oh, dear.
-What are you doing?
-Hi.
I'm reviewing the ledgers
from the old office.
Look at this, Mom.
My gosh.
This must have been taken on the day
he signed the Ulchiro office's lease.
-They're Ms. Cha and Mr. Koo, right?
-Yes.
Tae-poong.
How are you holding up?
I'm amazed you decided
to move out of the office.
I'm fine.
I just feel bad for my dad
and the employees.
But I badly needed that deposit
to try something new.
You know what?
It's nice to have people around.
It felt like it was over for the company
in the empty Ulchiro office,
but now that I can hear
people breathing and conversing,
I finally feel at ease.
That's why people flock together
and form a village.
People watch the television,
read the newspapers,
and go to cinemas
just to see how other people are doing.
-Mom.
-Yes?
What do you think
troubled my dad that badly?
Well…
Everyone running a business
suffered greatly.
That's my point.
My dad wasn't the type
to crack under the pressure of work
or losing a client, was he?
TYPHOON TRADING RELOCATION NOTICE
Man, this is just the place
for Tae-poong to burrow into.
What a dump.
MAILBOX
TO. BAE SONG-JUNG
What's with that lady?
Is she a thief or what?
There he is!
-Your food's here.
-You're quick as always.
Goodness. Who ordered tangsuyuk?
Seafood jjajangmyeon too?
-Who on earth placed this order?
-Me. I know how much you love shrimp.
-How much is it?
-It's 24,500 won.
Wait.
-Here we go.
-What the… What is wrong with you?
Why would you pour the sauce
all over the tangsuyuk?
-To enjoy it juicy and moist.
-It'll be soggy!
How could you be so reckless?
This is unacceptable, man.
-Surely, it can't be such a big deal--
-Just look at what you've done!
-You could've asked first.
-Shame on you.
MOMO'S PUB
Oh, dear.
Don't just stand there. Get in already.
Jeez.
Goodness.
Have some pickled radish.
I know you love them.
I can see through your tricks.
Take any more tangsuyuk,
and I'll hurt you.
Gosh.
Lead an honest life, okay?
Ms. Oh.
You're making me feel uncomfortable.
-What do you mean?
-You keep watching me.
You even gave me a tangsuyuk piece.
Because it was the piece you dropped.
Please stop liking me so much.
Oh, come on. It's not like that.
Tell him he's got it wrong.
Don't date, Ms. Oh.
Focus on your career
until I find one for you.
Then, you'll marry a nice man.
No, don't get married.
Enjoy your single life.
I'll do as you say.
That took a weight off my chest.
Why won't you tell them?
We're good colleagues, nothing more.
Please don't declare your love for me.
Don't order tangsuyuk
until we finish collecting the coupons.
We've almost reached our goal.
Thank you.
I know he's not the one you like.
I mean Mr. Bae.
EPISODE 11
TOMORROW COMES LOVE
Give up that ridiculous green juice gig
and come to work.
Look at him. Even Mr. Bae
comes in daily to work with us.
I'll have you know
that logistics requires a specialist.
It requires all sorts of expert knowledge.
Those with that expertise
are the top assets.
Come on, now. The company
can save a ton with one less employee.
What's this?
I've been reviewing the old ledgers.
But why? That's random.
Isn't this…
Man, it's from almost a decade ago.
ACCOUNT BOOK
If you realize you put down
the wrong amount in the ledger,
how do you generally proceed?
Supposing it was either a simple error
or that the order got canceled.
The golden rule was to strike it out
and get the late Mr. Kang's seal.
Or we reported the discrepancies
by the end of the month
and added an extra page
listing the corrections later.
Why? Did you find anything useful?
Hello?
Mr. Kang?
I couldn't find it.
I mean a deal that is stable,
dependable, and also lucrative.
I've had no luck yet.
So that's what you're after?
Such deals don't exist. Even if they did,
they'd never come our way.
If you think about it…
Government projects are still
the most reliable despite all this,
but it's not easy to sign them on.
-The government agencies?
-The public sector deals? Forget it.
We could never handle that now.
Only the large corporations do it.
Gosh, look at the time.
Oh, dear. I've got to go.
-Hey.
-"Public sector deals"?
Ms. Oh, remember that appointment
to visit our partner company?
Oh, right.
-Let's head out together.
-Okay.
MOMO'S PUB
Oh, dear.
It's called public procurement.
"Public procurement"?
Public procurement?
So, this is
the Public Procurement Service?
SAVE RESOURCES CAMPAIGN
I see tons of notices.
BID FOR DOMESTIC COMMODITIES
BID FOR FOREIGN COMMODITIES
BRIEFING ON "PLAINS OF HOPE"
This is tricky.
To my knowledge,
the PPS doesn't handle export.
There has to be something for us too.
I don't get why you brought me here.
You've always taken
Ms. Oh with you so far.
I asked you to come
because I haven't had time
to get to know you and stuff.
You know,
about Ms. Oh…
I know you two have
a special thing going on.
How can I miss it
when you're always together?
Oh, no. I wouldn't say
we've reached that level.
You're best friends, right?
So, about Ms. Oh.
Was she heartbroken by my demeanor?
-What the--
-Excuse me?
Oh, no. She wasn't heartbroken at all.
I believe men and women can be friends.
Please do all you can to console Ms. Oh.
Friends…
That's not how things are between us.
I hope you're not delusional
or think that everyone loves you.
-Sorry?
-You can hear me, can't you?
-Excuse me.
-Yes?
Could you direct me to the team
handling export-related projects?
I'm not sure if we have such projects.
Perhaps the Foreign Commodities Division?
Their office is over there.
-Okay, thank you.
-No problem.
Hello, I'm with KOICA.
"Bienvenue en Corée."
Welcome to Korea.
KOICA?
I studied French for my elective
foreign language course in high school.
My friends told me I have the look
of a European, especially a French man.
I was initially reluctant
to take up French,
but as time passed, I got the sense
that the language suited me rather well.
So…
Mr. Kang?
Man, look at all these people.
-Welcome.
-Sorry?
Please go in. We'll begin soon.
-I can wait here--
-You know how she is.
All right, everyone.
We'll begin the presentation shortly.
Please take a seat.
Please be seated.
Hello.
Jeez.
PUBLIC PROCUREMENT SERVICE
I apologize for the delay.
It's been a hectic day.
What was I thinking?
Mr. Jung. Could you go get my shoes?
I'm afraid we have to start, ma'am.
BRIEFING ON "PLAINS OF HOPE"
THE CONSTRUCTION PROJECT
FOR HOSPITALS AND SCHOOLS IN AFRICA
HOSTED BY: FOREIGN PROCUREMENT DIVISION 2
My heartfelt gratitude to everyone
for attending this event in person.
To make the most of your valued time,
I'll get straight to the point.
Hello and welcome. Thanks for coming.
Since time is precious,
we will keep this brief.
First, please welcome
the representatives from KOICA.
To my left, the organization
for international cooperation.
We also have the African delegation
who came all the way to Korea.
And to my right,
the delegation from Africa.
Welcome.
As you know, KOICA has decided
to fund the construction of schools
and hospitals with surgical facilities
to post-conflict regions in Africa.
Our agency will be procuring
the resources required for the project.
As you know, we have decided
to provide financial aid
for the construction
of schools and hospitals
in regions affected by the war.
We will purchase anything necessary
to support this effort.
Please check the document on your desk.
You can find
the list of items to be procured,
the project timeline,
contact information, and key guidelines.
"Gauze pad, X-ray film, ambu bag,
thermometer, surgical glove, oxygen tank…"
EQUIPMENT AND PURPOSE
As for the items procured
for this project,
our agency will collect them all
and ship them together to Africa.
Since that's the case,
please make sure to meet the deadline.
The agency is handling shipping?
Do you have any questions?
Excuse me.
Can I sign up for everything on the list?
Which company is he with, Mr. Jung?
He seems familiar,
but I can't say for sure.
To my knowledge,
we already have a vendor
for all the items on the list.
Mr. Jung. Are they any items
that haven't been decided?
Yes, there are.
Please make sure that you don't bid
on items assigned to another company.
Let's not get greedy, okay?
We're all here for a great cause.
-Let's keep it civil.
-Of course.
To be frank,
you all work at respectable firms.
Once this project concludes smoothly,
our African counterpart
will extend their invitations.
Can you remind me
what the top tourist spots are?
What is famous in your region?
Sahara Desert, safari…
Serengeti, lions.
They have the Sahara Desert, the safari,
the Serengeti, and the lions.
Lions?
"Global Exploration: The World of Nature."
No, you should keep it on a little longer.
You need to wear it for 15 minutes or more
to enhance your concentration.
It wasn't an easy decision
for me to buy it.
Beom, getting only 30 points
in the dictation test is a serious issue.
Keep it on, okay?
There's my good boy.
The nimblest and quickest predator
here in the African savanna
has its eye on only one thing.
There's no way I would let this go.
Did you see zebras and giraffes too?
Were you the lion chasing after them?
What exactly is your goal here?
A government project,
the most secure project.
Here you go. Please check this out.
CONSTRUCTION PROJECT
OF HOSPITALS AND SCHOOLS IN AFRICA
So, KOICA is launching
an aid project in Africa,
building schools and hospitals.
That's right.
They'll ship all
necessary items to Africa.
Just think about it.
This ship won't disappear,
the goods will never get seized,
and our client will never go under.
This is the perfect opportunity for us.
Of course, it's perfect.
But larger corporations generally have
monopoly on such fantastic deals.
"Monopoly"?
-Haven't you heard of it?
-Monopoly.
Anyhow, didn't you say
that they already have a vendor
for all of the items?
And yet…
one item is left hanging.
Surgical gloves.
-How come?
-There's no domestic supplier.
See? All the meaty, juicy parts
have been divvied up among them.
We would never get to have a bite.
Do you want to know why?
Because we lack the funds.
Have you got some?
What about personnel and experience?
FUNDS, PERSONNEL, EXPERIENCE
This requires quite a big sum.
Even if we got items on credit,
we still need a bid bond and a deposit.
Also, there's a mountain
of paperwork to submit. It's too much.
To my knowledge, we've never done
a deal in the public sector.
You might as well think the big companies
called dibs on such big projects.
They meet all three criteria.
Don't say that.
We have experience, at the very least.
If you're going to voice your opinion,
just come work here.
You're not a guest star.
Do you think we're 015B?
Ms. Cha, the green juice is expired.
Think of it as being aged and drink up.
Hear me out.
The late Mr. Kang and Mr. Koo
used to work for Samjeon Trading.
So, we did work on public sector projects
in the early days.
-My father did that?
-Sure.
Things would be better
if Mr. Koo were here, right?
But I must say, you guys have no respect.
How can you talk back
to your boss this much?
As the saying goes,
you can only come up with excuses
when you're trying to weasel out.
But where there's a will, there's a way.
I'm off.
See you.
-See you.
Come work with us already.
You can find a way for us.
KOO MYUNG-GWAN
I might be able
to find a way.
-Hello.
-Hello, we're with Typhoon Trading.
Please take this.
We just wanted to ask--
-Thank you.
Freight Elevator 3 will be going down
with the VIPs heading to the B3 lounge.
Does that make us very important cargo?
It must be tiring to repeat that all day.
You might as well rest back here.
Gosh.
I hold the doors open for the jerks
who are strangers.
It's nothing to hold the doors open
for the brats I work with.
We'd love you more
if only you were polite.
I already get enough attention
for my beauty.
I'd be in big trouble
if I get any prettier.
Pretty girl, you've got a run
in your tights again.
-Get a new pair, will you?
-I have a run on this side too.
A pair, huh?
It's a sure way to lose your luck.
Only those born with good luck
can afford to care about it.
Cover up your belly button
when you're out of the uniform.
That's none of your business.
You're unbelievable.
We've arrived at your lounge, dear VIPs.
Please exit here.
Thanks for the VIP treatment, pretty girl.
-She sure doesn't lack confidence.
-Doesn't it feel good, though?
Ma'am.
Excuse me.
-May I rearrange your hair?
-Excuse me?
I saw a bobby pin
stick out of your headscarf.
Just a second.
Let me take this…
Here we go.
The team's manager throws a fit
over minor details like this.
Nobody likes being nagged
when they're doing their best.
I'll be off, then.
Wait, miss.
Thank you.
No problem.
"Buhyeong Station, Exit 1."
And this is the Exit 1.
Do you think she meant
that we could meet him here?
She gave us the note for a reason.
Let's wait it out.
Right?
It's the new millennium.
Believe in the Prophet.
-New millennium, new sky.
-Exactly.
THE DIVINE SKY
Hello.
Millennium, the Prophet of the new age
I see a fortune in your face…
-Oh, my.
-Mr. Koo.
Tae-poong.
Mi-seon.
-What brings you here?
-Of course, we've come to see you.
We need your advice
on the Public Procurement Service.
Could you spare us a minute?
It won't take long.
I'm afraid I'm rather busy at the moment.
-I'll see you later.
-Wait, Mr. Koo.
NEW MILLENNIUM
SPECIAL PRAYER SERVICE
Rumor has it
that you're the CEO now, Tae-poong.
That's true.
-Congratulations, Mr. Kang.
-Goodness.
A NEW MILLENIUM
FOR THE DIVINE SKY
Hello.
-Hello.
Are you friends of Deacon Koo here?
That's right, sir.
We met by chance.
-Off you go, then.
-Mr. Kang, correct?
Yes?
I can see fortune in your face.
Pardon?
-Does he mean there's money?
-No.
He thinks you look lucky.
Oh, you meant good fortune.
My eyes can see everything,
and I mean everything.
He is the Prophet.
-Thank you, Mr. Prophet.
-That's not his name.
I've fallen victim
to crooks twice recently.
-So I--
-Are you sure you're not a lucky man?
I'm sure. I've been conned twice.
I lost my home and office--
Millennium
-The Prophet of the new age
-When the dejected feel like crying
-He soothes their souls
Wait, Mr. Koo.
-The Prophet lives inside us
-Step back
-Welcome him into your heart
NEW SKY
What's a millennium and a binary system?
Oh, dear Prophet
All rise to greet the Prophet
Believe in the Prophet.
All hail the Prophet!
Heed him well!
-Exalted on high
NEW MILLENIUM
SPECIAL PRAYER SERVICE
-Is our Prophet
-Millennium!
-Millennium
-The Prophet of the new age
Prophet!
-Nurse a hope
-That our Prophet
-Will save us from hardships
Deliver my message!
-The Prophet of hope
Step back!
-Step back, welcome him into your heart
-The new millennium
Who am I?
-Our Prophet
Who am I again?
-Dear Prophet
-Our dear Prophet
Tae-poong.
Is this plagiarized? The tune is familiar.
It does sound familiar.
How did you get here?
They welcomed us in when we showed these.
I can't believe you two.
-My gosh.
-No, wait.
-Look.
-That startled me.
Once upon a time,
a prophet appeared and declared,
"In the year 1999,
the lord of darkness
will descend onto your world."
"The lord of darkness
shall devour everything in the world."
"But do not fear."
"I have dispatched a being
with my authority and discerning eyes."
Thank you!
Everyone.
Who or what is the lord of darkness?
Who or what is this lord of darkness
that you fear so much?
War!
-Satan.
-The Gulf War.
-The IMF!
-Poverty!
No, you're all wrong!
The lord of darkness
is none other than Y2K.
It's Y2K.
A NEW MILLENIUM
FOR THE DIVINE SKY
Computers run on a binary system,
which consists of ones and zeros.
0, 0, 0, 0, 1, 1, 1, 0, 1, 0, 1, 0, 1, 0.
In other words, computers can't grasp
the concept of the new millennium.
When the clock hits 12:00 a.m.
on January 1st, 2000,
all computers will start malfunctioning!
All the missiles and nuclear weapons
rely on their computer system!
So the world…
It will go boom!
Please save us!
And yet,
the true path to the heavens
will soon appear before us.
OPENING THE PATH TO THE SKY
Just ten million won can make the systems
understand number two!
Oh, dear Prophet!
This is a sweet deal.
Surely, you don't want to keep it and
survive alone while your family perishes!
-Of course not!
-You're right!
Let us pray.
-About that deal with the PPS--
-They're praying.
I'm sorry, everyone.
They're securing goods
to construct schools and hospitals,
and most items on the list
have been claimed
except for surgical gloves.
All we need is to strike a deal
at a good price and hand the goods over.
But we're having difficulty
navigating the waters on our own.
You're the only one
who's ever worked with the PPS.
Exactly.
I really want to secure this… No.
We must secure that deal.
Please stop, Tae-poong.
How's this, Mr. Koo?
We'll show you the documents.
You can make your decision after that.
Then you'll see
it's a golden opportunity you can't miss.
-Join us already!
-Why, you…
Stop it, okay?!
Typhoon Trading doesn't even have
enough money to strike that deal!
We have spawns of Satan
harassing one of our own!
Drag them out!
Hang on.
This is just… Mr. Koo!
Let me go!
Folks, how lame is "Y2K"?
Just turn the computers off
and unplug them, okay?
Mr. Koo!
Wait, Mr. Koo!
Do you think he'll come back?
We've got to have faith.
With or without him,
I'm going to secure that deal.
Why do you want the PPS deal so badly?
I just have a hunch
that this may be the final shot for me.
Since I don't have more funds,
or anywhere to make a retreat,
I need a dependable client.
Let's go inside.
I told you we could get
something more delicious.
I happen to love dumplings.
-You do?
-Sure.
Thanks.
Is it good?
What's wrong? Are you okay?
Sip some water.
-Should I go get some medicine?
-No, I'm good.
Some water will do.
-Are you sure?
-I'm quite sure.
-Was there something in the dumpling?
-Oh, no.
I'm fine.
Let me try it.
Mr. Kang.
I'm usually the one looking out for others
and not the other way around.
I'm the opposite.
People tend to look out for me.
So…
it feels new to me
to have someone look out for me.
I honestly feel grateful too.
But I must say…
I don't want to be dependent
on such emotional comfort.
What I'm saying is…
How about we…
just look out for each other at work only?
Let's separate feelings from work.
-Separate feelings from work?
-That's it.
I want to pursue my career
more than anything, Mr. Kang.
I feel this is necessary.
-Dig in. The dumplings might get cold.
-Okay.
Take them slowly.
-So, did you come here to get some tights?
-No, I've come to see you.
I could've come to you after I was done.
I came because I could manage it.
-Hello.
-Hey, you're here.
I have an order
from Color Story in Gwangju.
-The order is for 233,000 won.
-I have them here.
You can check.
Here's 240,000 won, sir.
-The change is 7,000 won.
-Okay.
-Here's your 7,000 won.
-Thank you.
-Did you check everything?
-Sure.
Thank you.
-Thank you.
-Have a good one.
I gave it some thought afterwards.
Wouldn't it be unfair
to lose good luck over torn tights?
My sister works so hard every day.
Then again, older ladies
turn out to be right most of the time.
Mi-ho, I'll buy you 100 pairs of tights.
Really?
-Let's make it 1,000 pairs.
-Lucky me.
Open wide, Mi-ho.
Gosh, this is so nice and cold.
By the way, this place is bustling
with people, clothes, and money.
Right?
All the money in the country
seems to flow into this area.
TEXTILE ACCESSORIES MARKET
It's nice here.
I love clothes and money.
What would you do
if you had a lot of money?
Me?
I know what I'd do.
I want to fund Mi-seon's college tuition.
I've always been an airhead,
and she was the model student.
But Mi-seon had the bad luck
of being born first,
so I went to college, not her.
I hate it.
It feels like I owe her.
I'll make a lot of money,
so she can go to college.
What about you? What's your dream?
Me?
My dream is making it as a singer.
Are you serious?
Sing a song for me.
Come on. I can barely remember
what happened on Studio I Love You.
Here's my song
Now it's over
But that's in the past.
It's not what I want now.
Instead,
I have a new dream.
What's that?
You.
You are
my dream, Mi-ho.
SEOUL REGIONAL OFFICE
OF THE PUBLIC PROCUREMENT SERVICE
Sample containers, plaster cast kits…
Hochang, screens.
LIST OF VENDORS
What's this? Who are they?
"Typhoon Trading"?
Why do we have a small fish here?
Who gave them a call?
-Hey, Mr. Jung.
-Yes, ma'am?
-Did you bring in Typhoon Trading?
-No.
Fax them that they're not eligible.
Understood, ma'am.
TYPHOON TRADING, POWDERED SURGICAL GLOVES
SEOUL OFFICE
OF THE PUBLIC PROCUREMENT SERVICE
It's an official notice from the PPS.
"Bidding ineligibility notice."
"We inform that your company
is ineligible to bid on this project."
"End of note"?
They can't just kick us out.
Didn't I warn you?
I knew it would come to this.
Be rational.
It would be odd if they let any company
bid on a project on a national scale.
Our company only has four staff members.
How much do we have left?
We have 43,500,000 won, rounded down.
It's so specific. Now, I feel suffocated.
We must get this deal.
-Yes?
-What now?
-Hey!
-What's going on?
-My gosh!
-Jeez, I can't believe this!
-Come in already.
-Mr. Koo!
-Don't dawdle.
How have you been?
I bet you lounged around.
Couldn't you have come in
and helped us move stuff?
I did hear about the relocation.
But the office itself doesn't matter.
As long as we're all together,
that's Typhoon Trading.
He seems pretty fine.
No, the office matters.
-It affects my mood.
-Mr. Bae.
I see you've brought us
some presents again.
Darn it.
-Accept salvation.
-What's this?
What does Y2K mean? Who made this?
-What is it?
-Have you joined a church?
Here's your salvation, Mi-seon.
This isn't the time
to turn to religion, Myung-gwan.
Look at what we're dealing with.
BIDDING INELIGIBILITY NOTICE
File an appeal.
Pardon?
Tae-poong.
Civil servants operate
according to their own code.
What civil servants love and hate the most
is none other than due process.
It's about anti-competitive practices,
unfair trade, coercion of confidentiality…
and discrimination.
What?
They filed an appeal? On what grounds?
Apparently, they're claiming
the conditions of eligibility are unclear.
They'll also lodge a complaint
on "anti-competitive practices,
unfair trade, discrimination,
coercion of confidentiality,"
and any other grounds they can think of.
They've got to be joking.
What discrimination?
We just don't want any mishap.
-You can't be more right.
-Jeez, what a pain…
-Mr. Jung.
-Yes?
What was it again? The surgical gloves?
Has any other company
submitted a bid for them?
No, ma'am.
Tell them to come in.
It turned out all our orchids
had been overwatered.
Overwatered?
Yes.
The orchids kept growing,
but there was no room in the pots
while the soil was soaking up water.
Huge chunks of their roots rotted away.
That's why they couldn't bloom.
I see.
They seemed fine on the outside,
while the hidden parts were rotting away.
But still,
they survived
thanks to their strong roots.
Look.
I cut away all the rotten roots
and moved them to a bigger pot.
They then flowered right away.
Mr. Koo.
It's time you came back to our office.
We have a place for you here.
Hello?
Oh, I see. Understood.
Sure, thank you. Goodbye.
-They want us to come in to submit a bid.
-That's amazing.
-That's splendid.
-Mr. Koo's valuable advice paid off.
Does this CD contain instrumental songs?
Turn it off!
When we're down and lonely
Who will come to save us?
Our dear Prophet!
The lord of darkness will strike
on January 1st, 2000.
An apocalypse is coming!
Life as we know it will no longer exist
after December 31st, 1999!
You have to install this
to save yourselves and your families!
Listen, Ma-jin, Seon-taek, and Tae-poong.
-You must install this!
-Mr. Koo.
Millennium
The Prophet of the new age
This is for all the dejected
who feel like crying.
-Mr. Koo!
-Play the CD.
-Our Prophet is--
-Mr. Koo!
Please help us out.
Please help Typhoon Trading.
Mr. Koo…
Father.
Please shield them so they won't get hurt
by a worthless being like me.
Allow them to forget
a miserable failure like me forever…
and lead…
a happy life.
Please…
Please let them be happy.
Ms. Cha.
Hi there.
Gosh.
How come you're here all alone?
I'm waiting to hear from someone.
I volunteered to stay behind
and sent the others home.
-Can I get you a cup of tea?
-Sure, that sounds lovely.
You take after your father.
-You're sweet just like him.
-Sorry?
My father was sweet?
You bet he was.
He was so thoughtful and generous.
Mr. Koo used to be
the ruthless one around here.
Here you go.
Thanks.
You know…
By any chance…
did the late Mr. Kang
tell you something in secret
or entrust you with a special item?
-A special item?
-Did the late Mr. Kang…
Did he really not have
any emergency funds?
Could he have left you with something
you don't recognize the value of?
I was just curious.
The truth is…
There's nothing.
The bankbook I gave you was everything.
Of course, I should've known better.
Otherwise, you wouldn't have
given up our old office.
Ms. Cha.
If your current job is too rough on you,
you can join us anytime.
You spent 20 years
working for this company.
Goodness, dear.
Thanks for saying that.
Right, more than 20 years
have passed already.
You know what?
Turns out long years of service don't mean
you deserve a second chance.
I really liked your father.
-Not romantically, but as a colleague.
-Oh, of course.
I loved our company too.
That much is true.
Please remember that, okay?
What time is it?
-I should get going. It's late.
-Ms. Cha.
-You forgot your bag.
-Oh, right.
Ms. Cha, did you reorganize
the files in this office?
What do you mean? Why would I do that?
I took a look yesterday
and noticed how they were arranged
by date from right to left.
I know that's how you arrange files.
I guess someone tried your way, then.
Looks like it.
-Good night, then.
-Okay.
APPLIED BY:
TYPHOON TRADING, KANG TAE-POONG
Stamp my seal.
Press down hard.
Great. Now, here.
No errors, right?
Would you look at that?
Trying to expand to Africa, punk?
Ignore him.
Long time no see, Freckles.
Just ignore him.
No errors, right?
Is the total amount correct?
What on earth?
BIDDING APPLICATION
"Surgical gloves"?
We're filing for exports.
To the Public Procurement Service.
-Mr. Ha.
-Yes?
It will go well.
ORANGE JUICE
SURGICAL GLOVES
-Where's my seal?
-Here.
Right here.
APPLIED BY:
PYO MERCHANT MARINE, PYO HYUN-JUN
What do you think, Tae-poong?
SURGICAL GLOVES
What do you mean?
If you're scared,
we'll cancel the application,
be it yours or mine.
Are you backing out already?
Cancel yours, then.
Know your place. I'm getting tired now.
Let's play rock, paper, scissors
next time you feel like fooling around.
Sucks for you, but all I can think of
is pummeling you hard.
That way, you'd get to win
once out of ten rounds
when I accidentally make a mistake.
Excuse me.
What's this?
Pyo Merchant Marine was supposed
to procure orange juice, wasn't it?
That's right. But we just updated
the item to rubber gloves…
I mean, surgical gloves.
You can't make
last-minute changes like that.
-Then we'll export orange juice--
-Mr. Ha!
I'm going for the gloves.
Gloves it is, then.
But the gloves are taken.
The nit-picking Taeheung Trading
took the gloves.
-Typhoon Trading.
-Right, Typhoon Trade.
-It's Typhoon Trading.
This isn't your first rodeo.
Don't go back on your word
and ruin our meticulously crafted plans.
-Let's carry it out as arranged.
-Of course.
Listen, lady.
Why can't I make changes?
Excuse me? Listen very closely, mister.
I don't appreciate your tone.
I'm a Grade 6 civil servant
with Salary Grade 23.
He's simply curious, ma'am.
When we have multiple bidders
on the same item,
we must have competitive bidding.
-Competitive bidding?
-That's right.
What's that?
Each company will submit their price,
and we'll choose the lowest.
-The winner gets the deal.
-That's right.
But with this process,
both of you will sustain heavy losses.
That's exactly my point!
All right, then.
Here's an idea.
Why don't you make a compromise?
If one of you changes an item,
I'll offer favorable treatment for you.
-Especially on our next project.
-Great.
-I can assure you that.
-We'll do that.
We submitted our form first.
Don't we have the priority?
That's a load of crap.
There's no rule like that.
-Why, you little--
-All right, fine!
Let's have competitive bidding.
I might as well do it the right way
if there's no way around it.
You seem to know each other,
so mark my words.
I have two terms.
First, submission closes on the dot.
You're out if you miss
any required documents.
Second, the bid will be open 100%
with the lowest bidder winning.
You realize what this means, do you?
-Sure.
-Of course.
-You don't.
-Not in here.
Your father would be enraged.
Never mind him.
Just get me all the documents.
And check all the companies
producing surgical gloves
and secure all their stock for me.
Yes, sir.
PURCHASE SPECIFICATIONS
Let's see.
These are ready.
-Do we have enough funds for the bid bond?
-Of course.
Once we secure the deal,
we'll have to wire the deposit too.
We should take that into account.
Have you requested a quotation?
Yes, only three companies produce
the powdered surgical gloves
that meet KOICA's requirements.
-I've made the request to all three.
-Well done.
Everything hinges on price this time,
so quotations matter the most.
Those Pyo Merchant Marine punks
are a pain in our neck.
Why are they getting in our way?
-What's that?
-The translated manual for the gloves.
I don't understand why they would ask
the manual to be translated into French.
All the French phrases I know
are Sophie Marceau and La Boum.
Those two are it.
SPECIFICATION OF SURGICAL GLOVES
Mr. Go.
Look at this. How could they…
They wrote the translations by hand.
Who works this way? Are they crazy?
What's the matter with these people?
They should've typed everything
and sent us the printed copy.
Hold on. What can we do now?
Shouldn't we type every word ourselves?
Of course. But to do that,
we need the right keyboard.
-One that supports French.
-Yes, one that supports French.
-Where can we… Would Mr. Bae know?
-Hold on.
In that case…
Who should I call? Oh, right here.
TYPEWRITERS, COPIERS, FACSIMILE
I see. I got it loud and clear. Okay.
-Okay.
-Are we good?
-They managed to find it!
-Gosh, I can't believe they bought one.
-I can't believe they pulled it off.
-They're incredible.
-How are things moving along?
-Great.
Mr. Pyo.
About the update to the goods.
-Shouldn't we inform your father--
-Forget it.
My dad will only nag some more.
It's all going to be fine.
Look at me, Mr. Ha.
Come on.
You may find my dad hard to deal with,
but no parent wins against their child.
-Don't you worry.
-I won't, sir.
This is the golden opportunity
to make one of my dad's dreams come true.
-Where's that business card?
-Oh, right.
So, this is the surgical gloves company?
PRECAUTIONS FOR USE
"L'intervention…"
LIST OF DOCUMENTS TO SUBMIT
Okay, then…
-Are we all set?
-Here. Yes.
-We just need the manual.
-How much longer?
-We're almost done.
-We're nearly there.
-Are you done?
-Yes.
-Great.
-Are we ready?
-Ms. Oh, here…
-Print it.
-I'll hit the print button.
-Okay, I'll be right here.
PRINTING
-All right!
-Okay.
-You can be quite handy, man.
-I told you I'm a top-level asset.
Mr. Bae.
-Thanks for your trouble.
-You're welcome.
I'm glad we bought that keyboard.
-Yes, that really saved us.
-We owe this success to our joint efforts.
-I can't believe we managed to find this.
-It must've not been easy finding that.
Mr. Kang, look!
-Letters are broken up.
-What's the matter?
Look at these letters.
-What happened?
-Maybe the printer glitched.
-I'll try again.
-Was it the wrong button?
The machine may glitch on the first try.
-There. Check it out.
-Did you do it?
-What's going on here?
-Hold on.
-How…
-What's going on with these letters?
Is it a computer virus?
Wait, it's the font.
-Font?
-The software must not support this font.
What do we do then, Mr. Kang?
It's 2:00 a.m., isn't it?
We've got to find a way quickly.
-What options do we have?
-Reinstall the software?
Hold on. What do we do?
Have you been well?
Quick, give me my work sleeves!
Let's find his work sleeves.
Where are they?
TECHNICAL SHEET
He's copying the document faster
than I can type it.
You're great at drawing too. It's amazing.
I feel like I could wear that glove.
SHAPE AND STRUCTURE: DIMENSIONS
I can't believe
he's managing it in one go.
No one will doubt that's a glove.
RAW MATERIALS
POWDER: CORN
-It means corn.
-I see.
So, corn.
-That must mean "powdered corn."
-I guess powdered corn goes into gloves.
I don't mind corn.
I'm done.
Thank you for your hard work.
-You were amazing.
-Way to go, Mr. Koo.
I can't believe my eyes.
Incredible.
Thank you so much. Seriously…
-You did it, Myung-gwan.
-How cool is this?
Thank you. You were brilliant.
-Goodness, you sure are.
-Let's not touch them.
TECHNICAL DATA SHEET FOR SURGICAL GLOVES
Hey, that's not yet cooked.
When it comes to barbecue…
It's not easy, is it?
-Tell me about it.
-You're so clumsy.
-Let me take that.
-I can barely see.
-Hello.
-Welcome.
-Over here, Ms. Cha!
-Hey, welcome.
-Please take a seat.
-Right here, Ms. Cha.
-Goodness.
-You didn't have to invite me as well.
-Mr. Koo.
-Come on.
How could we not
when Mr. Koo saved the day?
-Let me pour you a glass.
-Okay.
Let me pour you one.
Now that you're here, make a toast for us.
It's been a while.
You'd like that? Okay.
What should I go with?
How about this?
-Let's go with "ILA."
-Okay.
All together, then. One, two…
-I!
It can be terribly exhausting.
-L!
Let's still hang in there…
-A!
And thrive!
-Cheers!
-Great.
-All right.
Wait until the meat turns brown, punk.
Uncooked meat can make you ill.
I'm genuinely concerned.
Did you submit the documents?
Listen. When I got there…
What was that shifty little punk's name?
Was it Ha?
That guy was walking over,
so I glared at him
to let him know
I was ready to take him down.
-I scared the hell out of him.
-He sure was charismatic.
Are you trying
to memorize the menu, Mr. Koo?
I can't decide
if I want noodles, the stew,
or the scorched rice soup.
-Shall we order more meat?
-Go ahead.
Ma'am, three portions of meat, please.
-Just two portions, please.
-Oh, come on.
Order some more. I want to take some home.
The decent thing to do
is take the leftovers.
Don't claim stuff from the get-go.
Come on,
my kid is a senior in high school.
Wrap these up for now.
-Take them home.
-Thanks.
It looks so good.
Mr. Koo.
No, that's okay.
I'd say these are all cooked.
It's not good for your health
to overcook the meat.
It can increase the risk of cancer.
You're a know-it-all.
Mr. Koo, have some coffee.
Thank you.
I wanted to get some air. That's all.
Goodness.
Thank you for what you've done today.
The idea of copying the notes by hand
didn't even occur to me.
It was nothing.
Back in the day,
we used to complete all forms by hand,
whatever document it was.
Mr. Koo.
What Typhoon Trading needs at the moment
is a tree rather than a flower.
Trees can give you shelter
from the sun in summer
and a warm layer of leaves in fall.
In winter,
they can even give us some firewood.
I'd appreciate a sturdy tree
with layers of growth rings.
I can't recall what they called it.
I'm not the sharpest, you see.
Take your time and join us back in.
You have to come back in.
Growth rings, huh?
He must be talking about experience.
I prefer Job's tears tea.
Get up now.
-See you tomorrow.
-See you, Mr. Koo.
-Get home safely.
-Stop wandering and come to work!
-Good night.
-Hey, driver!
-Our ride is here.
-Jeez, you dummy.
-Let me in!
-He's a handful. Hey, you.
-We're sharing the car!
-Hey, punk.
I can't get out now.
I'll give you the taxi fare.
I'll get you a taxi too, Seon-taek.
-No, please.
-I'll pay double!
We're paying double, darn it!
-This is our ride.
-Sorry.
-You can take the taxi.
-Goodness.
-I'm not sure--
-Get in there, Seon-taek.
You don't have to double the rate.
I can't believe you.
-Here we go.
-Hey, wait.
-Take this.
-What's this? Oh, no.
I insist. Take it.
I'm not taking it back!
-Listen, Seon-taek.
-Yes?
I know you've got your husband and kid,
but prioritize yourself, okay?
You're unbelievable.
Your folks might not be around,
but you have us.
You can go now.
Off you go!
Thank you.
-Thanks again!
-Get home safely.
-Thank you!
-No problem.
Goodbye.
-Taxi!
-Mi-seon.
-Mi-seon!
-Double the rate!
-I'll quadruple the rate!
-Here, Mi-seon.
-What?
-No, I'll pay eightfold!
Are you getting on? Go ahead, sirs.
I'm taking the subway.
-I see. Get home safely.
-Oh, goodbye.
-Don't squabble, okay?
-Okay, we won't.
Good night.
It sure felt like the old days
to have everyone together.
Do you want to walk together for a bit?
Sure.
Thanks.
I've given it a thought.
I can't do that.
I can't pretend like
what happened between us never happened.
Do you dislike me, Mi-seon?
No, I don't dislike you at all.
I just don't feel comfortable
when the air goes mellow around us.
You should just take it easy--
You don't get to decide how I feel.
My feelings for you won't change.
Feel this. My heart is racing.
-It's because I like being with you.
-I get it, okay?
I'm going to like you,
and my feelings will only grow stronger.
Don't you worry. I won't let
my feelings interfere with work.
Yes, I'm the CEO,
and you're my senior staff.
Yes.
Jeez.
But know this.
You should know…
that I…
I love you.
Although it's one-sided.
It's my first unrequited love.
TOMORROW COMES LOVE
TYPHOON FAMILY
Starting today, I'll act on my feelings.
Where do I start?
You think I can pull it off?
Those surgical gloves
are made in one place in the US.
That's a monopoly.
If the starting lines aren't the same,
maybe we take a step ahead.
What's most precious to you, Ms. Oh?
And you, Mr. Kang?
What matters most to you?
While you were quiet,
you made this mess?
It's not over yet.
Even if I take a few jabs,
one uppercut from me and he's done.
Please! Ms. Oh!
Oh Mi-seon!
Subtitle translation by: Jeongwoo Kim